Professional Profile

A certified Prince 2 Practitioner Project Manager with a proven automotive and retail multi-store FMCG management expertise, genuine business acumen, and an excellent track record managing large teams. Excels at implementing delivery strategies, new concepts, and projects, delivering projects on time and to budget in fast-paced, competitive, and ever-changing environments.

Skills

- Cross functional and Stakeholder Management
- Coaching, motivational and team-building skills
- Six Sigma Green Belt
- Prince 2 Practitioner
- Project planning and problem management
- Agile & Waterfall

Career Summary

Director/System Lead - Infotainment Jaguar Land Rover November 2019 - Present

Accountable for the delivery and maintenance of the Infotainment software base platform through the engineering product lifecycle through to launch.

Main Responsibilities

- Manages a cross functional technical team to identify and analyse issues through to root cause.
- Able to use problem solving techniques to deconstruct complex problems and communicate to non technical teams. Propose solutions and control mechanisms.
- Puts the customer first in all activities, work with Quality and Service networks to resolve customer complaints and issues quickly.
- Plans and implement automation and vehicle test streams to assure software robustness.
- Reports software status to senior managers and programme. Assess and mitigate risk.
- Managed conflict resolution where areas of responsibility and issue root cause are unclear for severe and critical issues.
- Delivered software component to agreed time and quality for all vehicle lines on the 'P-IVI' infotainment rollout plan.

Director/Defect Manager Infotainment DR Consultancy Ltd./Jaguar Land Rover December 2017 - Present

Accountable for the management of software defects during the development and integration process. Primarily responsible for managing and coordinating activities with software validation teams, project teams, interfacing module engineers, as well as company quality, both in UK and worldwide.

Main Responsibilities

- Manage delivery of automotive software components through product engineering gateways through to launch
- Lead internal and external technical developer teams and partner suppliers internationally to deliver software products on time and to budget.
- Use data mining and analysis techniques to identify and report issues, risks and common themes.
- Drive efficient throughput against KPIs (time to progress/monitor & remove waste)
- Track, measure, forecast and report milestone status for key gateways to senior management and programme. Identify, analyse and manage risk.

- Coach teams in best practice.
- Track and measure all projects, Triage, Development, Test, Change. Report metrics and plans to improve.
- Supported the transition to new software toolsets, organising and conducting training sessions to
 encourage user adoption. Hosted focus groups and feedback sessions to improve on subsequent roll out
 waves.

Project/Site Manager

Wickes Ltd., /Travis Perkins GroupJune 2016 - December 2017

Reporting to the Regional Director, lead a £12m retail operation to deliver sustained business growth. Support the organisation's 5-year plan for increased market share and increased revenues in the building and DIY retail sector.

Achievements

- Site/Business recovery. Increased monthly sales volume average 16% month on month for financial year 2017
- Project managed 3 concurrent site refits to generate projected £5m sales uplift per site through showroom refit programme June 2017.
- Increased site customer service scores by 40% to top 10 percentile

Main Responsibilities

- Full Profit and Loss accountability.
- Financial management including budgeting, forecasting, and obtaining funds from sponsors.
- Management of internal and external cross-functional teams in a project environment.
- Deliver objectives to strict budgets, deadlines, and service agreements.
- Recruit, train, develop and motivate site teams at scale on new operating practices following site wide transformation.
- Produce and implement plans to reduce risk and improve business performance, creating milestones and key performance indicators.
- Successfully led and implemented store sales strategies, marketing campaigns, seasonal events and promotions
- Devised and delivered a balanced set of KPIs, monitoring adverse performance and implementing action plans
- Key account management coupled with negotiating buying strategies with suppliers and manufacturers.
- Ability to communicate and present at board level strong numeracy skills, performance review and trend analysis/statistical presentation skills

General Manager Dixons Retail August 2008 – June 2016

Well respected Senior Retail Manager within the group. Experienced in managing stores and providing business improvement through project secondment and 'troubleshooting'.

Achievements

- Project managed 2 Dixons megastore refits to roll out the 2 in 1 Currys/PC World model, on time and to budget.
- Planned, developed, and managed the implementation of new business and operational processes for concept site format megastore resulting in a 40% reduction in operational labour cost being best in class in the UK.
- Planned and implemented site wide training plans, delivering at scale. This included onboarding supplier
- Planned, organised and led major event programmes for company products at the NEC and The Gadget Show Live
- Introduced operational efficiencies into Knowhow brand repair process reducing turnaround time by 27%.
- Pioneered pilot time and attendance system saving projected £11k per annum on payroll spend per site. Subsequently, this led to a nationwide roll out.
- Improved store sales turnover by 22% p.a. through identifying site layout improvements, producing best fit model adopted nationally for stand-alone PC World Stores.
- Created and drove a people centric culture, improving colleague engagement scores from 59% to 89% over 24-month period and customer service score consistently outperforming the group.

Main Responsibilities

- Manage multiple business unit interdependencies including internal vendors and concessions
- Recruited, developed, and trained cross functional teams, identifying talent, and implementing succession planning
- Coach, develop and manage department managers to achieve business KPIs and improve their own performance
- Capitalised on direct sales channel opportunities to deliver average YOY business growth of £2.5m
- Highly process driven with extensive experience in stock/inventory management and cost saving measures.

Historical Employment

- Sainsbury's, West Midlands Deputy Store Manager -September 2005 August 2008.
- Hammerwich Construction Project Co-Ordinator July 2005 September 2005.
- B&Q, Stechford Gardening and Seasonal Manager July 2004 July 2005.
- Tesco Plc, Various -Department Manager April 1999 July 2004.

Qualifications

- Prince2 Foundation and Practitioner 2017
- BA (Hons.) Business Management and Professional Development University of Derby Corporate-2014